ALI PAJAND

Montreal, Quebec/Canada ali.pajand@gmail.com



Senior Frontend Developer

Summary

I'm an extroverted, energetic, highly positive and hardworking developer with expertise in web development specific to the frontend side with a history of graphics knowledge.

My main aim is to learn about the web and new technologies from various sources. I believe users should experience a rich and thought-through form of art whereas developers should be making use of reusable and simple codes.

Work Experience

Mar 2018 - Present

Senior Frontend Developer

Ctrl+Tech

⇒ Implement websites and admin panels for: (You can find me on each project: SITE_URL/humans.txt)

- https://Tazebar.com
- https://Ctrltech.com
- https://Admartiz.com
- https://Banikar.com
- https://Techtoman.com
- o https://Bidzila.com
- https://FirouzehPlat.com
- Sahamdaran: {https://saham.iidic.com}
- ⇒ Implement PWA application for "Tazebar.com" and "Techtoman.com"
- ⇒ Implement attractive online chat based on vue js
- ⇒ Rewrite old Applications and maintain and Fix bugs of them
- ⇒ Design and implement email template
- ⇒ Implement custom service worker
- ⇒ Work with Firebase messaging
- **⇔** Write Documents
- ⇒ Write BDD tests for project

Jan 2014 - Dec 2017 Frontend Developer

Rayvarz Software Engineering

- Working in BPMS team (business process management system to rewrite online admin panel and portal in vuejs)
- Design pattern mentoring, UI Discussion and prepare prototype for programmers
- Working in BPMS team as frontend developer (business process management system to rewrite online admin panel and portal in Vue.js)
- Collaborate on service catalogue for Ministry of Economic Affairs of Iran
- Change user interface of eOffice to create new sense and change admin panel arguments and texts
- Maintenance of old eOffice application and add feature
- Start to implement new website version of rayvarz
- Try to integrate UI of all products in whole company

Jun 2013 - Sep 2013 Internship Frontend Developer

Unilever (Iran Department)

Help to develop and maintain the global application

Remote Experiences

Frontend Developer (Vancouver Area, Canada) Apr 2019 - Jul 2019

Timelv

Help to develop and maintain the global application

Jan 2015 - Jan 2017 Front-end Developer (Lahti Area, Finland)

Lahtiprecision

⇒ Implementing three generation of website + Maintenance of website

Education

Sep 2014 - Aug 2018 M.Sc. Computer/Information Technology Administration

Allame Tabataba'i University

Thesis: Identification of Factors to Use Cloud Computing by University Students in **Educational Process**

- **Next** is my favorite ssr framework in vue

- State management tools like **Redux**

Sep 2010 - Aug 2014 B.Sc. Engineering/Industrial Management

Allame Tabataba'i University

Skills

Vue js | Nuxt js React is | Next is | Gatsby

- **Nuxt** is my favorite ssr framework in vue
- State management tools like **Vuex**
- Familiar with typescript
- Familiar with typescript

Unit Tests React Native

Familiar with typescript BDD and TDD tests with **Jest**, **Mocha** and **E2E**

Notifications and Service Workers Progressive Web Apps (PWA)

Services like Onesignal and Google Firebase Experience enough by working with PWA and Workbox

Version Controller Python (Django) & Nodejs

Working with Git, SVN and TFS - Familiar as a backend background and web api